const arr = [{"id":0,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"Mild hypochromic microcytic anemia is associated with which of the following pathologies?","answers":[{"option":"Vitamin B12 deficiency","bool":false},{"option":"Beta-thalassemia major","bool":false},{"option":"Alpha-thalassemia minor","bool":true},{"option":"Diamond-Blackfan anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Hemoglobin H disease","bool":false}]},{"id":1,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"Which of these act as an opsonin?","answers":[{"option":"C3a","bool":false},{"option":"C5a","bool":false},{"option":"Leukotriene B4","bool":false},{"option":"Cytokines","bool":false},{"option":"Fc portion of IgG","bool":true}]},{"id":2,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"Which of the following cells are involved in the formation of epithelioid cells and giant cells in granulomatous inflammation?","answers":[{"option":"Macrophages","bool":true},{"option":"B cells","bool":false},{"option":"Epithelial cells","bool":false},{"option":"T cells","bool":false},{"option":"Plasma cells","bool":false}]},{"id":3,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"Which parasite causes blackwater fever and cerebral malaria?","answers":[{"option":"Plasmodium malariae","bool":false},{"option":"Plasmodium ovale","bool":false},{"option":"Plasmodium vivax","bool":false},{"option":"Plasmodium falciparum","bool":true},{"option":"Plasmodium knowlesi","bool":false}]},{"id":4,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"Which system reaches the functional state first in the embryo?","answers":[{"option":"Respiratory","bool":false},{"option":"Skeletal","bool":false},{"option":"Excretory","bool":false},{"option":"Nervous","bool":false},{"option":"Cardiovascular","bool":true}]},{"id":5,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"Where are white infarcts usually seen?","answers":[{"option":"Spleen","bool":true},{"option":"Testes","bool":false},{"option":"Ovaries","bool":false},{"option":"Lungs","bool":false},{"option":"Small intestine","bool":false}]},{"id":6,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"Where does red infarct usually occur in?","answers":[{"option":"Heart","bool":false},{"option":"Venous occlusion","bool":true},{"option":"Arterial occlusion","bool":false},{"option":"Spleen","bool":false},{"option":"Kidney","bool":false}]},{"id":7,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"Which of the following is covered by pseudostratified columnar epithelium?","answers":[{"option":"Spleen","bool":false},{"option":"Palatine tonsil","bool":false},{"option":"Pharyngeal tonsil","bool":true},{"option":"Lymph nodes","bool":false},{"option":"Lingual tonsil","bool":false}]},{"id":8,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"Which one of the following is a plasma mediator?","answers":[{"option":"Histamine and nitric oxide (NO)","bool":false},{"option":"Prostaglandins","bool":false},{"option":"Leukotrienes","bool":false},{"option":"Chemokines","bool":false},{"option":"Complement proteins","bool":true}]},{"id":9,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"The breakdown of heme produces which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Amino acids","bool":false},{"option":"Globulin","bool":false},{"option":"Glucose","bool":false},{"option":"Bile","bool":false},{"option":"Bilirubin","bool":true}]},{"id":10,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"Heme is broken down in which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Liver","bool":true},{"option":"Kidney","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Stomach","bool":false},{"option":"Bone marrow","bool":false}]},{"id":11,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"Erythropoietin is mainly produced in which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Spleen","bool":false},{"option":"Bone marrow","bool":false},{"option":"Liver","bool":false},{"option":"Kidney","bool":true},{"option":"Adrenal gland","bool":false}]},{"id":12,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"Which drug is used for the reversal of heparin?","answers":[{"option":"Warfarin","bool":false},{"option":"Protamine sulfate","bool":true},{"option":"Bivalirudin","bool":false},{"option":"Enoxaparin","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin K","bool":false}]},{"id":13,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"Which of the following is considered normal bleeding time?","answers":[{"option":"30-50 seconds","bool":false},{"option":"15-20 minutes","bool":false},{"option":"6-20 minutes","bool":false},{"option":"2-5 minutes","bool":true},{"option":"5-10 minutes","bool":false}]},{"id":14,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"Which of the following is true for hemophilia B?","answers":[{"option":"Can be transmitted from father to daughter","bool":false},{"option":"Is characterized by a marked decrease in coagulation time","bool":false},{"option":"Also called Christmas disease","bool":true},{"option":"Can be treated by anticoagulants","bool":false},{"option":"Is an autosomal disorder","bool":false}]},{"id":15,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"In which disease is the conjugated bilirubin not being transported outside the liver?","answers":[{"option":"Hemolytic anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Dubin Johnson syndrome","bool":true},{"option":"Gilberts syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Criglar Najjar syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Physiological Jaundice of the newborn","bool":false}]},{"id":16,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"Which factor takes part in the intrinsic pathway?","answers":[{"option":"Heparin-like factor","bool":false},{"option":"Rheumatoid factor","bool":false},{"option":"Factor II","bool":false},{"option":"Hageman factor","bool":true},{"option":"Factor VII","bool":false}]},{"id":17,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"Which of the following is a major plasma protein?","answers":[{"option":"Transferrin","bool":false},{"option":"Prothrombin","bool":false},{"option":"Haptoglobin","bool":false},{"option":"Albumin","bool":true},{"option":"Immunoglobulin","bool":false}]},{"id":18,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"Which of the following characteristic is INCORRECT about basophils?","answers":[{"option":"Contain major basic proteins","bool":true},{"option":"Releases histamine","bool":false},{"option":"Has basophilic cytoplasm","bool":false},{"option":"Contains blue/purple staining granules","bool":false},{"option":"contains lobed nucleus","bool":false}]},{"id":19,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"Which of the following is a precursor for plasma cells?","answers":[{"option":"B lymphocytes","bool":true},{"option":"Megakaryocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Platelets","bool":false},{"option":"Red blood cells","bool":false},{"option":"T lymphocytes","bool":false}]},{"id":20,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"The specialized epithelium is present in which of the following lymphoid organ?","answers":[{"option":"Lymphoid tissue","bool":false},{"option":"Tonsils","bool":false},{"option":"Spleen","bool":false},{"option":"Lymph nodes","bool":false},{"option":"Thymus","bool":true}]},{"id":21,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"Cytotoxic T cells destroy microbes in which part of the cell?","answers":[{"option":"Smooth endoplasmic reticulum","bool":false},{"option":"Rough endoplasmic reticulum","bool":false},{"option":"Golgi Apparatus","bool":false},{"option":"Cell membrane","bool":false},{"option":"Cytoplasm","bool":true}]},{"id":22,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"Major cationic protein is present in the granules of which cell?","answers":[{"option":"Neutrophils","bool":false},{"option":"Basophils","bool":false},{"option":"Mast cells","bool":false},{"option":"Monocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Eosinophils","bool":true}]},{"id":23,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"Which of the following substances is a plasminogen activator inhibitor?","answers":[{"option":"Vitamin K","bool":false},{"option":"Urokinase","bool":false},{"option":"Aminocaproic acid","bool":true},{"option":"Streptokinase","bool":false},{"option":"Fresh frozen plasma","bool":false}]},{"id":24,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"Which type of antibodies are found in tears and saliva?","answers":[{"option":"IgA","bool":true},{"option":"IgG","bool":false},{"option":"IgD","bool":false},{"option":"IgM","bool":false},{"option":"IgE","bool":false}]},{"id":25,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"Hemolytic anemia is the result of which hypersensitivity reaction?","answers":[{"option":"Type 5","bool":false},{"option":"Type 2","bool":true},{"option":"Type 4","bool":false},{"option":"Type 3","bool":false},{"option":"Type 1","bool":false}]},{"id":26,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"Which of the following is not an anticancer drug?","answers":[{"option":"Bleomycin","bool":false},{"option":"Etoposide","bool":false},{"option":"Dactinomycin","bool":false},{"option":"Streptomycin","bool":true},{"option":"Vinblastine","bool":false}]},{"id":27,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"Hemopoiesis is production of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Red blood cells","bool":false},{"option":"Platelets","bool":false},{"option":"Stem cells","bool":false},{"option":"White blood cells","bool":false},{"option":"All blood cells","bool":true}]},{"id":28,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"Which anti-TB drug is given parenterally?","answers":[{"option":"Streptomycin","bool":true},{"option":"Isoniazid","bool":false},{"option":"Ethambutol","bool":false},{"option":"Rifampin","bool":false},{"option":"Pyrazinamide","bool":false}]},{"id":29,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"Blood plasma level is maintained by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Plasma proteins","bool":true},{"option":"Estrogen","bool":false},{"option":"Thyroxine","bool":false},{"option":"Testosterone","bool":false},{"option":"RBCs","bool":false}]},{"id":30,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"Which of the following is involved in the inhibition of chemotaxis?","answers":[{"option":"C3a and C5a","bool":false},{"option":"Tumor necrosis factor(TNF) and Interleukin-1","bool":false},{"option":"Lipoxin","bool":true},{"option":"Prostaglandins","bool":false},{"option":"Chemokine","bool":false}]},{"id":31,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"Leukotrienes are synthesized by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Cyclooxygenase-1 (COX-1)","bool":false},{"option":"Prostaglandins","bool":false},{"option":"Cyclooxygenase 2 (COX-2)","bool":false},{"option":"Lipoxygenase","bool":true},{"option":"Phospholipase A2","bool":false}]},{"id":32,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"Which of the following is the incorrect statement regarding granulocytes?","answers":[{"option":"They contain non-specific azurophilic granules","bool":false},{"option":"They contain a single nucleus with multiple lobes","bool":false},{"option":"Granulocytes are also called myeloid cells","bool":false},{"option":"The term polymorph refers to eosinophils","bool":true},{"option":"They contain specific granules","bool":false}]},{"id":33,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"Which of the following is the correct statement regarding the cell cycle?","answers":[{"option":"S phase is DNA replication phase","bool":true},{"option":"G2 is the same as the mitotic phase","bool":false},{"option":"I phase is the mitotic phase","bool":false},{"option":"S phase is synthesis of organelles","bool":false},{"option":"G1 is premitotic phase","bool":false}]},{"id":34,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"Primary health care involves which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Justice, equity, resources","bool":false},{"option":"Justice, fairness, ethics","bool":false},{"option":"Planning, effictivness, fairness","bool":false},{"option":"Resources, planning, situation analysis","bool":false},{"option":"Equity, effectiveness, efficiency","bool":true}]},{"id":35,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"How many amino acids does alpha-hemoglobin have?","answers":[{"option":"141","bool":true},{"option":"118","bool":false},{"option":"115","bool":false},{"option":"184","bool":false},{"option":"162","bool":false}]},{"id":36,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"What are the first identified cells of red blood cells (RBC) series?","answers":[{"option":"Thrombocyte","bool":false},{"option":"Proerythroblasts","bool":true},{"option":"Normoblasts","bool":false},{"option":"Polychromatic erythroblasts","bool":false},{"option":"Reticulocyte","bool":false}]},{"id":37,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"Radicals are physiologically formed in which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Phagolysosomes","bool":true},{"option":"Mitochondrion","bool":false},{"option":"Proteins","bool":false},{"option":"Cell membrane","bool":false}]},{"id":38,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"Type-1 hypersensitivity involves which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Neutrophil","bool":false},{"option":"IgG","bool":false},{"option":"Basophil","bool":false},{"option":"IgA","bool":false},{"option":"Mast cell","bool":true}]},{"id":39,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"Which test is not neccessary in initial diagnosis of hemoglobin deficiency?","answers":[{"option":"Blood smear","bool":false},{"option":"WBC count","bool":false},{"option":"Platelet count","bool":false},{"option":"Bone marrow","bool":true},{"option":"RBC indices","bool":false}]},{"id":40,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"What is the daily requirement for Vitamin B12?","answers":[{"option":"2-3 μg","bool":true},{"option":"0.05-1 μg","bool":false},{"option":"30-35 μg","bool":false},{"option":"80-100 μg","bool":false},{"option":"10-15 μg","bool":false}]},{"id":41,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"Which immunosuppressant is also a IL-2 inhibitor?","answers":[{"option":"Mofetil","bool":false},{"option":"Cyclosporine","bool":true},{"option":"Sirolimus","bool":false},{"option":"Daclizumab","bool":false},{"option":"Azathioprine","bool":false}]},{"id":42,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"What does not cause the cobalamin deficiency?","answers":[{"option":"Inadequate diet","bool":false},{"option":"Tape worm infection","bool":false},{"option":"Esophagitis","bool":true},{"option":"Pernicious Anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Deficiency of intrinsic factor","bool":false}]},{"id":43,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"Which of the following drug is not topical?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Streptomycin","bool":true},{"option":"Nitroglycerin","bool":false},{"option":"Lidocaine","bool":false},{"option":"Estradiol","bool":false}]},{"id":44,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"In which of the following conditions, round, microcytic, and hypochromic red blood cells are not usually seen in?","answers":[{"option":"Sideroblastic anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Hereditary spherocytosis","bool":true},{"option":"Beta thalassemia major","bool":false},{"option":"Iron deficiency anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Beta thalassemia minor","bool":false}]},{"id":45,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"Which of the following anti-cancer drug is not a cell cycle specific?","answers":[{"option":"Methotrexate","bool":false},{"option":"Bleomycin","bool":false},{"option":"Cyclophosphamide","bool":true},{"option":"Vinblastine","bool":false},{"option":"Vincristine","bool":false}]},{"id":46,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"A 32-year-old female presented to OPD with bleeding gums, epistaxis, and non-palpable rashes. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Von Willebrand disease","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin K deficiency","bool":false},{"option":"Hemophilia B","bool":false},{"option":"Platelet disorder","bool":true},{"option":"Hemophilia A","bool":false}]},{"id":47,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"What does anemia in thalassemia lead to?","answers":[{"option":"Convulsions","bool":false},{"option":"Skeletal deformities","bool":true},{"option":"Protuberant abdomen","bool":false},{"option":"Stunted growth","bool":false},{"option":"Genetic mutations","bool":false}]},{"id":48,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"Which of the following is the gold standard diagnostic test for thalassemia?","answers":[{"option":"Complete blood count (CBC)","bool":false},{"option":"Hemoglobin electrophoresis","bool":true},{"option":"Polymerase chain reaction","bool":false},{"option":"Peripheral blood smear","bool":false},{"option":"Red cell distribution width (RDW)","bool":false}]},{"id":49,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"Where does intrinsic factor release from?","answers":[{"option":"Interstitial cells of Cajal","bool":false},{"option":"Pacemaker cells of the GI tract","bool":false},{"option":"Parietal Cells of the stomach","bool":true},{"option":"D1 cells of pancreas","bool":false},{"option":"Interstitial cells of Leydig","bool":false}]},{"id":50,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"What is not a common pathway of metastasis?","answers":[{"option":"Local invasion","bool":true},{"option":"Seeding to body cavity","bool":false},{"option":"Seeding to other body surfaces","bool":false},{"option":"Hematogenous spread","bool":false},{"option":"Lymphatic spread","bool":false}]},{"id":51,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"Which of the agents are responsible for causing cancer?","answers":[{"option":"Adenoviruses","bool":false},{"option":"Blood transfusion","bool":false},{"option":"Mutagens","bool":false},{"option":"Nicotine","bool":false},{"option":"Carcinogens","bool":true}]},{"id":52,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"What is pyrrole made up of?","answers":[{"option":"2 Succinyl COA","bool":false},{"option":"2 Succinyl CoA + 2 glycine","bool":true},{"option":"2 Glycine","bool":false},{"option":"2 Hb beta chains","bool":false},{"option":"2 Hb alpha chains","bool":false}]},{"id":53,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"Which of the following statements regarding the role of retinoblastoma (Rb) gene during the cell cycle is correct?","answers":[{"option":"It promotes the transition from G2 to M phase","bool":false},{"option":"It inhibits the transition from G2 to M phase","bool":false},{"option":"It promotes the transition from M to G₀ phase","bool":false},{"option":"It inhibits the transition from G1 to S phase","bool":true},{"option":"It promotes the transition from G1 to S phase","bool":false}]},{"id":54,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"The parents of a child with iron-deficiency anemia are being counseled regarding dietary modifications. Which of the following food items should be added to the diet of this child?","answers":[{"option":"Rice","bool":false},{"option":"Tea","bool":false},{"option":"High-fiber diet","bool":false},{"option":"Citrus fruits","bool":true},{"option":"Legumes","bool":false}]},{"id":55,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"Gastrectomy requires a lifelong administration of what?","answers":[{"option":"Vitamin B-6","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin A","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin D","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin B-12","bool":true},{"option":"Vitamin C","bool":false}]},{"id":56,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"Which of the following is considered as negative reinforcement?","answers":[{"option":"Punishment will prevent the repetition of behavior","bool":false},{"option":"Punishment will encourage the repetition of positive behavior","bool":false},{"option":"Removal of reward prevent the repetition of behavior","bool":false},{"option":"Removal of painful situation will encourage the repetition of behavior","bool":true},{"option":"Reward will prevent the repetition of negative behavior","bool":false}]},{"id":57,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"What is another name for operant conditioning?","answers":[{"option":"Instrumental conditioning","bool":true},{"option":"Classical conditioning","bool":false},{"option":"Pavlovian Conditioning","bool":false},{"option":"Observational learning","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":58,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"Which of the following is not responsible for the tensile strength of a wound during healing?","answers":[{"option":"Collagen cross linking","bool":false},{"option":"Structural collagen modifications","bool":false},{"option":"Increase in the size of collagen fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Collagen fibrosis","bool":true},{"option":"Collagen synthesis","bool":false}]},{"id":59,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"What does a deficiency of C1 esterase inhibitor lead to?","answers":[{"option":"Episodes of edema that never resolve","bool":true},{"option":"Urticaria is a presenting feature","bool":false},{"option":"Decrease immunity","bool":false},{"option":"Delay in immune response","bool":false},{"option":"Increase in anaphylatoxins","bool":false}]},{"id":60,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"What is the correct function of Fab fragment of antibodies?","answers":[{"option":"Antigen binding","bool":true},{"option":"Binding to specific proteins","bool":false},{"option":"All of these are functions of Fab","bool":false},{"option":"Binding to cells receptors","bool":false},{"option":"Binding to complement proteins","bool":false}]},{"id":61,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"Which of the following is not a part of the vascular events of acute inflammation?","answers":[{"option":"Stasis","bool":false},{"option":"Increased vascular permeability","bool":false},{"option":"Diapedesis","bool":false},{"option":"Attraction of leukocytes to the site of injury","bool":false},{"option":"Migration of endothelial cells","bool":true}]},{"id":62,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"Which of the following is prolonged by the administration of low-dose heparin?","answers":[{"option":"Activated partial thromboplastin time (aPTT)","bool":true},{"option":"Clotting time","bool":false},{"option":"Bleeding time","bool":false},{"option":"Prothrombin time (PT)","bool":false},{"option":"Bleeding time and prothrombin time (PT)","bool":false}]},{"id":63,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"Which one of the following enzymes is dependent on vitamin K to help in the formation of coagulation factors?","answers":[{"option":"Dehydrogenase","bool":false},{"option":"Carboxylase","bool":true},{"option":"Oxidase","bool":false},{"option":"Transferase","bool":false},{"option":"Decarboxylase","bool":false}]},{"id":64,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"How does cimetidine inhibit warfarin?","answers":[{"option":"By decreasing warfarin metabolism","bool":false},{"option":"Increasing warfarin metabolism/breakdown","bool":true},{"option":"By increasing anticoagulants","bool":false},{"option":"By enhancing erythropoiesis","bool":false},{"option":"By decreasing antithrombin III formation","bool":false}]},{"id":65,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"All the cells of blood originate from which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Colony forming unit","bool":false},{"option":"Committed stem cells","bool":false},{"option":"Growth and differentiation inducer cells","bool":false},{"option":"Megakaryocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Pluripotent hematopoietic stem cells","bool":true}]},{"id":66,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"What is the average sum of squares of the deviation about mean, divided by N is called?","answers":[{"option":"Mean deviation","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Variance","bool":true},{"option":"Absolute deviation","bool":false},{"option":"Standard deviation","bool":false}]},{"id":67,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"Which drug is bacteriostatic but becomes bactericidal if given in high doses?","answers":[{"option":"Capreomycin","bool":false},{"option":"Isoniazid","bool":false},{"option":"Chloramphenicol","bool":true},{"option":"Pyrazinamide","bool":false},{"option":"Rifampicin","bool":false}]},{"id":68,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"Which malarial parasite causes severe malaria?","answers":[{"option":"Plasmodium malariae","bool":false},{"option":"Plasmodium falciparum","bool":true},{"option":"Plasmodium vivax","bool":false},{"option":"Plasmodium ovale","bool":false},{"option":"Plasmodium knowlesi","bool":false}]},{"id":69,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"Regarding DiGeorge syndrome, select the inappropriate one:","answers":[{"option":"Defect in 3rd & 4th pharyngeal pouch","bool":false},{"option":"B cell immunodeficiency syndrome","bool":true},{"option":"Tetany","bool":false},{"option":"T cell immunodeficiency syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Heart and blood vessel enlargement","bool":false}]},{"id":70,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"What is the normal bleeding time in the Duke method?","answers":[{"option":"10-15 minutes","bool":false},{"option":"15-30 seconds","bool":false},{"option":"1-6 minutes","bool":true},{"option":"5-10 minutes","bool":false},{"option":"2-8 minute","bool":false}]},{"id":71,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"Interferon gamma activates which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"T cells","bool":false},{"option":"B cells","bool":false},{"option":"Macrophages","bool":true},{"option":"Mast cells","bool":false},{"option":"Basophils","bool":false}]},{"id":72,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"Lymphoid organ with outer darkly staining and inner lightly staining with patches of acidophilic type?","answers":[{"option":"Bone marrow","bool":false},{"option":"Spleen","bool":false},{"option":"Liver","bool":false},{"option":"Thymus","bool":true},{"option":"Lymph node","bool":false}]},{"id":73,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"The thymus is derived from which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"4th pharyngeal pouch","bool":false},{"option":"1st pharyngeal pouch","bool":false},{"option":"3rd pharyngeal pouch","bool":true},{"option":"2nd pharyngeal arch","bool":false},{"option":"5th pharengeal arch","bool":false}]},{"id":74,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"A person contains both type A and B antibodies. What would his blood group be?","answers":[{"option":"A-","bool":false},{"option":"AB+","bool":false},{"option":"D","bool":false},{"option":"O-","bool":true},{"option":"B+","bool":false}]},{"id":75,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"Which of the following vitamins do the clotting factors II, VII, IX, and X depend on for their synthesis?","answers":[{"option":"Vitamin E","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin K","bool":true},{"option":"Vitamin B","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin D","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin A","bool":false}]},{"id":76,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"What is the volume of the formed elements in blood?","answers":[{"option":"55%","bool":false},{"option":"28%","bool":false},{"option":"35%","bool":false},{"option":"45%","bool":true},{"option":"33%","bool":false}]},{"id":77,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"Which of the following is a major source of vitamin K?","answers":[{"option":"Green leafy vegetables","bool":true},{"option":"Mother's milk","bool":false},{"option":"Meat","bool":false},{"option":"Date","bool":false},{"option":"Fish","bool":false}]},{"id":78,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"Which of the following is not related to inflammation?","answers":[{"option":"COX-1","bool":false},{"option":"Lipoxin","bool":false},{"option":"COX-2","bool":false},{"option":"Thromboxane","bool":true},{"option":"Prostacyclin","bool":false}]},{"id":79,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"Which of the following is the best test for the diagnosis of malaria?","answers":[{"option":"Microbiological culture","bool":false},{"option":"Enzyme-linked immunoassay (ELISA) test","bool":false},{"option":"Thick and thin film","bool":true},{"option":"Serologic test","bool":false},{"option":"Pap smear","bool":false}]},{"id":80,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"What is the major function of complement protein C1?","answers":[{"option":"Agglutination","bool":false},{"option":"Binding to Fc IgG and IgM","bool":true},{"option":"Opsonisation","bool":false},{"option":"Neutrophil chemotactic agent","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":81,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"Which of the following induces contraction of endothelial cells to increase vascular permeability?","answers":[{"option":"Prostaglandins","bool":false},{"option":"Fibrin","bool":false},{"option":"Histamine","bool":true},{"option":"Vascular endothelial growth factor","bool":false},{"option":"Serotonin","bool":false}]},{"id":82,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"Which of the following is wrong regarding Wiskott Aldrich syndrome?","answers":[{"option":"It is X-linked dominant","bool":true},{"option":"Associated with WASP gene","bool":false},{"option":"Causes patches across skin","bool":false},{"option":"It is an immune deficiency","bool":false},{"option":"Associated with T-cell defects","bool":false}]},{"id":83,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"Which one of the following is not among the main cells that are involved in chronic inflammation?","answers":[{"option":"Neutrophils","bool":true},{"option":"Macrophages","bool":false},{"option":"Lymphocytes","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Plasma cells","bool":false}]},{"id":84,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"Which diagnostic test is done for megaloblastic anemia?","answers":[{"option":"Complete blood count","bool":false},{"option":"Prothrombin time","bool":false},{"option":"Homocysteine levels","bool":false},{"option":"Serum folic acid and B12","bool":true},{"option":"Methylmalonic acid levels","bool":false}]},{"id":85,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"High amounts of which of these make up the cell walls of the gram-positive bacteria?","answers":[{"option":"Proteins","bool":false},{"option":"Peptidoglycans","bool":true},{"option":"Glycerol phosphate","bool":false},{"option":"Lipopolysaccharide","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":86,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"What is passive transport?","answers":[{"option":"From low to high gradient","bool":false},{"option":"From high to low gradient using ATP","bool":false},{"option":"From low to high using ATP","bool":false},{"option":"From low to high across a membrane","bool":false},{"option":"From high to low gradient","bool":true}]},{"id":87,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"A woman took aspirin while being pregnant. What would its effect be?","answers":[{"option":"Gastric ulcer","bool":false},{"option":"Closure of ductus arteriosus","bool":true},{"option":"Post partum hemorrhage","bool":false},{"option":"Congenital Anomalies","bool":false},{"option":"No effect","bool":false}]},{"id":88,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"What is major histocompatibility complex (MHC) genes present on?","answers":[{"option":"Short arm of chromosome number 8","bool":false},{"option":"Short arm of chromosome number 13","bool":false},{"option":"Short arm of chromosome number 6","bool":true},{"option":"Long arm of chromosome number 21","bool":false},{"option":"Long arm of chromosome number 4","bool":false}]},{"id":89,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"What is the most major histocompatibility complex (MHC) class for transplant determination?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"MHC class II","bool":false},{"option":"MHC class I","bool":true},{"option":"MHC class III","bool":false},{"option":"All of these","bool":false}]},{"id":90,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"Which coagulation factor is deficient in hemophilia A?","answers":[{"option":"XI","bool":false},{"option":"VIII","bool":true},{"option":"IX","bool":false},{"option":"II","bool":false},{"option":"V","bool":false}]},{"id":91,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"Which of the following are Major histocompatibility complex (MHC) Class II alleles?","answers":[{"option":"HLA-DR, HLA-DQ, HL-C","bool":false},{"option":"HLA-A, HLA-B, HL-C","bool":false},{"option":"HLA-DR, HLA-DQ, HL-DP","bool":true},{"option":"HLA-A, HLB-DQ, HL-DP","bool":false},{"option":"C2, C4, TNF","bool":false}]},{"id":92,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"What do Major histocompatibility complex (MHC) class III loci consists of?","answers":[{"option":"HLA-A, HLA-B, HLA-C","bool":false},{"option":"C2, C4, TNF, LT","bool":true},{"option":"HLA-DP, HLA-DQ, HLA-DR","bool":false},{"option":"HLA-DP, HLA-B, HLA-DR","bool":false},{"option":"C5a, C3a, C4","bool":false}]},{"id":93,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"Which of the following are the signs of contact dermatitis?","answers":[{"option":"Skin ulcers","bool":false},{"option":"Uremia","bool":false},{"option":"Inflammation with blisters","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Fever","bool":false}]},{"id":94,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"What is prenatal age?","answers":[{"option":"From 6 months after conception to birth","bool":false},{"option":"From 3 months after conception to birth","bool":false},{"option":"From conception to birth","bool":true},{"option":"After birth","bool":false},{"option":"From birth till 1 year after","bool":false}]},{"id":95,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"Which of the following is correct regarding erythrocytes?","answers":[{"option":"They consume the oxygen they carry","bool":false},{"option":"They are hemoglobin containing pigments","bool":false},{"option":"They form ATP anaerobically","bool":true},{"option":"Are nucleated cells","bool":false},{"option":"Become macrocytes in infection","bool":false}]},{"id":96,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"Obstructive jaundice leads to the deficiency of:","answers":[{"option":"Ca+2 ions","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin B12","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin K","bool":true},{"option":"Vitamin C","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin B9","bool":false}]},{"id":97,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"Lymphadenopathy is most commonly seen in which of the following regions?","answers":[{"option":"Neck","bool":true},{"option":"Arms","bool":false},{"option":"Head","bool":false},{"option":"Abdomen","bool":false},{"option":"Chest","bool":false}]},{"id":98,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"What defects are found in hereditary spherocytosis?","answers":[{"option":"Improperly formed or weak spectrin, band 3, 4.2, and ankyrin proteins","bool":true},{"option":"Hyperchromic and microcytic red blood cells","bool":false},{"option":"Hypochromic and microcytic red blood cells","bool":false},{"option":"Hyperchromic red blood cells and weak spectrin","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":99,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"What are ferritin and hemosiderin classified as?","answers":[{"option":"Iron binding proteins","bool":false},{"option":"Plasma iron","bool":false},{"option":"Transport form of iron","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Stored form of iron","bool":true}]},{"id":100,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"Which of the following is an example of a type IV hypersensitivity reaction?","answers":[{"option":"Systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE)","bool":false},{"option":"Arthus reaction","bool":false},{"option":"Graves disease","bool":false},{"option":"Contact dermatitis","bool":true},{"option":"Serum sickness","bool":false}]},{"id":101,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"Which is incorrect about type III hypersensitivity?","answers":[{"option":"Involve antigen-antibody reactions","bool":false},{"option":"Immune complexes formed are in circulation","bool":false},{"option":"They are also formed in extravascular tissues","bool":false},{"option":"Immune complexes are formed only in circulation","bool":true},{"option":"This type of reaction occurs in SLE","bool":false}]},{"id":102,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"A secondary case is infected by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Quaternary case","bool":false},{"option":"Primary case","bool":true},{"option":"Another secondary case","bool":false},{"option":"Tertiary case","bool":false},{"option":"None of the options are correct","bool":false}]},{"id":103,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"How would 'index case' be defined?","answers":[{"option":"An average case","bool":false},{"option":"Most symptomatic case","bool":false},{"option":"Least symptomatic case","bool":false},{"option":"First identified case","bool":true},{"option":"Most lethal case","bool":false}]},{"id":104,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"Which of the following is incorrect regarding secondary immunodeficiencies?","answers":[{"option":"Most common form is AIDS","bool":false},{"option":"Occur later in life","bool":false},{"option":"Result from infections, malnutrition, or treatment","bool":false},{"option":"Can cause an increased incidence of certain cancers","bool":false},{"option":"They are genetically determined","bool":true}]},{"id":105,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"Which of the following agents directly activates plasminogen?","answers":[{"option":"Streptokinase","bool":false},{"option":"Urokinase","bool":true},{"option":"Tissue plasminogen activator (tPA)","bool":false},{"option":"Heparin","bool":false},{"option":"Warfarin","bool":false}]},{"id":106,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"Which of the following are involved in type-2 hypersensitivity reactions?","answers":[{"option":"Antigen-antibody complexes","bool":false},{"option":"CD4 cells","bool":false},{"option":"IgE immunoglobulins","bool":false},{"option":"CD8 cells","bool":false},{"option":"IgG immunoglobulins","bool":true}]},{"id":107,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"What are the antibodies involved in immediate hypersensitivity?","answers":[{"option":"IgE","bool":true},{"option":"IgD","bool":false},{"option":"IgM","bool":false},{"option":"IgA","bool":false},{"option":"IgG","bool":false}]},{"id":108,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"Which drug inhibits the ADP pathway of the platelet aggregation?","answers":[{"option":"Clopidogrel","bool":true},{"option":"Aspirin","bool":false},{"option":"Abciximab","bool":false},{"option":"Tirofiban","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":109,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"Protein C and S are involved in which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Enhancing chemotaxis","bool":false},{"option":"Decreasing bleeding time","bool":false},{"option":"Clotting","bool":false},{"option":"Cleavage of clotting factors","bool":true},{"option":"Fibrinolysis","bool":false}]},{"id":110,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"Which of the following is an example of gamma globulins in circulation?","answers":[{"option":"Immunoglobulin","bool":true},{"option":"Agglutinogen","bool":false},{"option":"Alpha-fetoprotein (AFP)","bool":false},{"option":"Transferrin","bool":false},{"option":"Albumin","bool":false}]},{"id":111,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"Von Willibrand factor (VWF) is responsible for which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Production of collagen","bool":false},{"option":"Production of cytokines","bool":false},{"option":"Attachment of platelets to endothelial wall","bool":true},{"option":"Repair of endothelium","bool":false},{"option":"Attachment of platelets to each other","bool":false}]},{"id":112,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"Which of the following is true regarding Bruton's disease?","answers":[{"option":"Is charectarized by defect in phagolysosome synthesis","bool":false},{"option":"B cells are not affected","bool":false},{"option":"Is autosomal dominent","bool":false},{"option":"B cells undergo maturation","bool":false},{"option":"T cells are not affected","bool":true}]},{"id":113,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"Which of the following cells' development is impaired in severe combined immunodeficiency (SCID)?","answers":[{"option":"NK cells, B cells and T cells","bool":false},{"option":"NK cells and B cells","bool":false},{"option":"T cells only","bool":false},{"option":"T cells and B cells","bool":true},{"option":"NK cells only","bool":false}]},{"id":114,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"Pick the incorrect statement regarding leukocytes:","answers":[{"option":"They have one multilobed nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"They are nonspecific phagocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Macrophages and neutrophils are important phagocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Leukocytes are functionally active in circulation","bool":true},{"option":"Some contain specific granules","bool":false}]},{"id":115,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"Pick the incorrect statement about leukocytes:","answers":[{"option":"Neutrophils are polymorph","bool":false},{"option":"Granulocytes can be differentiated by stain","bool":false},{"option":"Eosinophils are anti-parasitic","bool":false},{"option":"Granulocytes originate from myeloid lineage","bool":false},{"option":"Neutrophil specific granules have affinity for methylene blue","bool":true}]},{"id":116,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"Which of the following is correct about red blood cells (RBCs)?","answers":[{"option":"They contain all usual cellular organelles","bool":false},{"option":"They contain carbonic anhydrase","bool":true},{"option":"Their first stage of development is the reticulocyte","bool":false},{"option":"They are nucleated","bool":false},{"option":"They generate energy primarily via lipolysis","bool":false}]},{"id":117,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"Erythropoietin is primarily formed in which organ?","answers":[{"option":"Bone marrow","bool":false},{"option":"Kidneys","bool":true},{"option":"Liver","bool":false},{"option":"Brain","bool":false},{"option":"Spleen","bool":false}]},{"id":118,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"Which antibody is found in the respiratory and digestive lining, as well as the saliva, tears, and breast milk?","answers":[{"option":"IgD","bool":false},{"option":"IgE","bool":false},{"option":"IgG","bool":false},{"option":"IgM","bool":false},{"option":"IgA","bool":true}]},{"id":119,"info":"1st-year/blood/2017","question":"Palatine tonsil is derived from which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"3rd pharyngeal arch","bool":false},{"option":"3rd pharyngeal pouch","bool":false},{"option":"2nd pharyngeal arch","bool":false},{"option":"2nd pharyngeal pouch","bool":true},{"option":"1st pharyngeal pouch","bool":false}]}]
export default arr